JON STOCKSDALE

jstocksdale@gmail.com 458 Glenhill Drive, Red Bank, TN 37415 423-598-6212 rafikisystems.com/stocksdale

Vision

Compassionate, Visionary, Creative, Hard-working, Learner, best at big picture tasks but willing to do almost anything to make a project succeed.

Entrepreneurial Educator and Database/Software Developer with extensive international experience, using my unique background, innovative thinking and understanding of people, technology and data to improve schools, businesses, and non-profits, and to positively impact environmental, economic and social issues.

Skills/ Experience

WEB/DATABASE/SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

- Programming, design and development with numerous languages and technologies
- Most recent projects include utilization of:
 - o SQL, ANGULAR, DART, C#, Elixir, GitHub, Javascript, HTML, SCSS
- Comfortable learning languages and technologies
- Recently developed uniquely secure and flexible school management system
- Comfortable with front and back end development, especially designing whole systems focused on user information needs and processes

EDUCATOR/CURRICULUM DEVELOPER

- Primary, secondary, and tertiary teaching, including:
 - Computer/technology courses (AP, HTML, CSS, Javascript, Java, Elixir, Office, Design/Visual Communications: Photoshop, InDesign, Illustrator)
 - Social Sciences (Psychology, Current World Issues, Government/Economics, MUN)
 - o Mathematics (Algebra 1, 2, Pre-Calculus, Middle School)
- Academic Support (K-12): Tutoring, Mentoring, Advising, Guidance Counseling
- Curriculum Development: Communications and Information Technology courses, Current World Issues course, and Psychology course
- Vision/Concern for appropriate use of educational technology and struggling students
- Currently mentoring women and minorities in Elixir functional programming curriculum

DATA ARCHITECT

- Adept designer of Relational Databases, especially creative data organization for better applications and analysis
- Designed unique generic solution: "Graph" Database linked to traditional SQL Relational Databases with security implemented through relationship patterns

DATA ANALYSIS

- Energized by statistical analysis, especially identifying essential research questions.
- Fluent in a wide range of tools, software, and languages, especially SQL

TECHNOLOGY IMPLEMENTER

 Deployed various technologies for budget-concious schools and businesses, including deploying and managing "one-to-one" computer implementation over the past decade

ENTREPRENEUR/INNOVATOR

Started or contributed to the start of various businesses, ministries, and departments;
 encouraged new ways of doing and thinking in established organizations

Work
History

USXPRESS/MODIS - Chattanooga, TN Sept 2019 – Present Data Architect – SQL Server development RAFIKI SYSTEMS - Chattanooga, TN Jan 2016 - Present Secure and uniquely connected database software for schools and other industries SODDY DAISY HIGH SCHOOL - Soddy Daisy, TN Jan 2019 – May 2019 • Math teacher (Algebra 1 and 2) for struggling/failing students RIFT VALLEY ACADEMY – Kijabe, Kenya (East Africa) Feb 1990 – Dec 2018 Administration (Guidance, Academic Support Coordinator, Department Head, Systems Administrator, Technology Coodinator, other "Get Stuff Done" roles) Teacher (Psychology, Computer Science, Economics/Current World Issues, Mathematics) Software/Database Development and Administration (SQL Server, Oracle, MS Access, Excel, Moodle, PowerSchool, Navision, Naviance, using SQL, C#/ASP.NET, VB, VBA) COMPUTER HORIZONS - Chattanooga, TN 1997 – 1998 Consultant/Software Developer (Access and SQL Server databases) for BCBST GEORGIA DUCK AND CORDAGE MILL - Atlanta, GA 1991 - 1994 Consultant/Software Developer (Visual Basic, Progress, MFGPRO, Paradox, SQL) BEN & JERRY'S OF INDIANA - Indianapolis, IN 1989 - 1990 Management and Point of Sale Implementation INSTRUCTIONAL COMPUTER EQUIPMENT – Indianapolis, IN 1983 - 1988 Software Development (C): developed graphics editor (pre-Photoshop) used by Herron School of Art, and interactive curriculum (pre-web) development tool for teachers Business and Education Technology Consulting and Development (various technologies) TAYLOR UNIVERSITY - Upland, IN 1981 - 1983 Student Information System development (Taylor University and Marion College) INDIANA VOCATIONAL AND TECHNICAL COLLEGE - Marion, IN 1982 - 1983 Instructor - Introduction to Computer Science and Programming GEORGIA STATE UNIVERSITY - Atlanta, GA 1994 MS Educational Psychology INDIANA UNIVERSITY – Indianapolis, IN 1990 • Teaching Certification (Mathematics 5-12) CHRISTIAN THEOLOGICAL SEMINARY – Indianapolis, IN 1985 Bible and Psychology TAYLOR UNIVERSITY – Upland, IN 1983 BA Mathematics, Psychology (minors: Computer Science, Political Science)

Life

Education

30 YEARS LIVING/WORKING IN AFRICA, MARRIED TO SUSAN SINCE 1991, 2 KIDS (19 AND 21), 2 DOGS INTERESTS/HOBBIES: PHOTOGRAPHY, HIKING, COFFEE ROASTING, WOODWORKING, READING, LEARNING, GLOBAL TRAVEL, BICYCLED THROUGH US, EUROPE, AND AFRICA (~30 COUNTRIES)

VOLUNTEER: TEACHER/TUTOR (PROGRAMMING, MATH, ESL, ROBOTICS, BIBLE), BUILDING, SURVEYING GENERAL CONTRACTOR FOR PERSONAL HOME IN KENYA

ENGAGING WITH OTHER COMPASSIONATE, COMMUNITY-FOCUSED CHURCHES, NON-PROFITS, & INDIVIDUALS